NAM NGUYEN, Full stack web developer

813-420-2585 | namnguyendevfl990@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio | GitHub

SUMMARY

I am a full-stack developer proficient in Html, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, Typescript, React, React hooks, Node, Express, Postgrel. I have ten years of experience in medicine, which allowed me to develop my logical thinking, problem solving, decision making, collaboration and conflict resolution skills. I also have a strong interest in computer programming, and I had a period of time learning Pascal programming language and developed basic programming skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front end: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, React, Redux, Next.js,

Back end: Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, Knex.js, Restful API Endpoints, Test-driven development with

Mocha + Chai.

Development environment: DBeaver.

Misc: 2FA with Speakeasy, Twilio, and Nodemailer; Argon2.

PROJECTS

- 1. **Flashcard-o-matic** [<u>Github server</u> | <u>Demo</u>]: a fullstack web app to help users create different decks and cards Built with Typescript, Next.js, Redux, Node, Express, PostgreSQL..
 - Designed the front-end layout using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, React, Next.js.
 - Built an API following RESTful design principles using Node, Express.
 - Implemented database connection using Knex, migrated new tables and completed CRUD routes
 - Implemented 2FA with speakeasy, nodemailer and Twilio when users forgot their passwords.
 - Hashed user passwords using Argon2.
 - Deployed the project to Vercel.
- 2. **We love movies** [<u>Github server</u> | <u>Demo</u>]: a fullstack web app to help users review showing movies and theaters where they can watch them
 - Built with React.js, Node, Express, PostgreSQL..
 - Built an API following RESTful design principles using Node, Express.
 - Implemented database connection by knex, migrated new tables and completed CRUD routes
 - Deployed the project to Heroku.
- 3. **Restaurant reservation** [<u>Github server</u> | <u>Demo</u>]: a fullstack web where restaurant personnel can add customer's reservations into the system
 - Designed the front-end layout using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, React..
 - Built an API following RESTful design principles using Node, Express.
 - Implemented database connection by knex, migrated new tables and completed CRUD routes
 - Deployed the project to Vercel

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Full-stack Web Developer Training | Thinkful | Remote | 8/2021 - Present

• Learned industry best practices and web development standards with a focus on HTML5, CSS, Javascript, React, Node, Express, Postgrel, Knex, data structures and algorithm.

Subinternship, Internal Medicine | Larkin Community Hospital | Miami, Fl | 02/2019 - 02/2020

- Took patient histories and performed physical exams
- Discussed reasonable diagnoses and treatments with the attending
- Wrote patient notes after rounding with the attending

EDUCATION

Certificate, ECFMG | 09/05/2019

• Passed a series of USMLE exams including USMLE step 1 and step 2

Doctor of Medicine | University of Medicine and Pharmacy in Ho Chi Minh city | Ho Chi Minh city, VietNam | 2008-2014